

### **OMAR ABDUL AZIZ**

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMPUTER SYSTEM AND NETWORK), UNIVERSITY OF MALAYA

### CONTACT

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

omarothman.co@gmail

+6017-638-0078

in omar.othman

omarothman.tech

## PERSONAL PROFILE

Experienced with a number of career highlights throughout the previous years. My achievements was spearheaded with dedication to meeting the industry needs.

Extremely motivated to constantly develop my skills and grow professionally throughout my career journey and I am confident in my skills & ability to contribute to the technology industry.

### LANGUAGE

English - Speaking & Writing

Bahasa Malaysia - Speaking & Writing

### **EDUCATION**

**University of Malaya** 

**CGPA** - 3.50

Dean's List - 3 Semesters

**Selangor Matriculation College CGPA** - 3.53

SMK Seri Ampang, KL

**SPM** - 7As

**PT3** - 5As

### **EXTRA COURSES**

### **Cisco Course Completion & Certifications**

- CCNA Routing & Switching
- CCNA Security
- CCNA R&S Wireless Essentials
- CCNA Enterprise Networking

#### **Enrolled / Joined**

- HackThisSite.org(Ethical Hacking)
- AlgoExpert

# COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

### Progamming Language & Framework







Python

Java

HTML







PHP

MySQL

Laravel

### **Operating System**





MS Windows

Cisco OS





Kali Linux

GNS3

### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

### **Kaspersky Security Deployment Engineer (2021)**

- Part time Kaspersky Endpoint Security Deployment Engineer
- Deployed the endpoint in 6,000 devices cumulatively in 4
   Jabatan Kerja Raya (JKR) branches.
- Lead a small team to manage the deployment at the HQ
- Attend and resolve technical issues related to the installation and deployment of Endpoint Security
- Provide solution and troubleshooting to any problem while performing the installation.

## ACADEMICS COURSE TAKEN

### **Networking & Security**

- Advanced Network Technology
- Network Security
- Computer Penetration
- Cryptography

- Mobile Computing
- Internet Technology
- Operating System
- Internet Technology

### **System & Others**

- Microprocessor
- Embedded Programming
- Data Structures
- Software Modelling
- Algorithm Design
- Database
- Project Management
- Soft Computing

### REFEREE

Dr. Muhammad Reza Z'aba

Senior Lecturer Faculty of Computer Science & IT +603 7967 2507

reza.zaba@um.edu.my

Mr. Nor Asrul Mohd Noor
Director of Aswant Solution

+6012-2073454

norasrul@aswant-solution.com

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

### Internship - MyMIT Integration Sdn Bhd (2020-2021)

- System Engineer Intern
- Responsible in developing & maintaining software products (web application) for clients both in government and private sectors
- Responsible in maintaining hardware products (server & networking equipment)
- Currently collaborating with this company in the Final Year Project Healthcare Management System Using Blockchain

### **MyTech Career Convention UM (2019)**

- Event Manager for MyTech Tech Talk
- Responsible in managing a tech forum event including invitation of VIP speakers, marketing and sales

### **EXTRACURRICULAR**

#### 2019-2020

- Volunteer of International Student (China) Registration (COVID-19 S.O.P Fully Implemented)
- · Elected as the Vice Director of UMalaya Radio
- Bowling Athlete of Sukan Mahasiswa Universiti Malaya (SUKMUM), bronze medalist
- Dean's Cup Open (Futsal) Gold Medalist
- Active member of Persatuan Komputer UM (PEKOM)

### 2018-2019

- DJ and Reporter of UMalaya Radio
- Head of Media Department in the faculty's Social Engagement Project
- Emcee of Malam Anugerah Za'ba (College Dinner)
- Joined Sukan Mahasiswa Universiti Malaya (SUKMUM) representing 7th College in Tenpin Bowling
- President of Tenpin Bowling, 7th College

### 2017-2018

- Anugerah Tokoh Dinamika of College Matriculation of Selangor receiver
- Participated in Robotics (Arduino) Competition
- Head of Contingent of Selangor Matriculation College's athletes
- Participated in college's annual charity (visiting the old folks' home Puchong)